♪ SHINY SWORD, MY DIAMOND ♪
( singing in Japanese )
♪ IT’S TIME ♪
♪
( goblins chuckling,
chattering )
( Eugeo gasping )
Kirito: COME ON.
( goblins laughing )
( Eugeo gasps )
Kirito: EUGEO, CALM DOWN.
( Eugeo grunts )
Kirito: WHEN I COUNT THREE,
WE’LL CHARGE
PAST THE FOUR GUYS COMING
AND KNOCK OUT THEIR FIRES.
Eugeo: O-OKAY.
Kirito: YOU CAN USE
THAT THING FOR LIGHT.
WHEN THE FIRES GO OUT,
FIND A SWORD, AND GRAB IT.
LEAVE THE BIG GUY TO ME.
HE WON’T GO DOWN EASY,
SO KEEP THE OTHERS OFF MY BACK.
Eugeo: BUT I-I NEVER FOUGHT
WITH A SWORD BEFORE.
Kirito: SWING IT LIKE YOUR AX.
COME ON!
ONE...
TWO...
THREE!
( yells )
( goblin grunts )
( goblins grunting )
Leader: HMM?
HMM?
Kirito: EUGEO!
DON’T THINK!
JUST START SWINGING!
Eugeo: HE MAKES IT
SOUND SO EASY.
( goblins gasp )
( goblins stammering )
Eugeo: I-IT’S THE LIGHT.
THEY’RE AFRAID OF THE LIGHT!
( ice tinkling )
( leader roars )
I AM THE GREAT UGACHI,
THE LIZARD KILLER.
YOU DARE CHALLENGE ME?
Kirito: I’M NOT
JUST GONNA CHALLENGE YOU.
I’LL KILL YOU!
( Ugachi growls )
Kirito: HAH!
( woman vocalizing )
( Ugachi growls )
Kirito: SWORD SKILL...
SHARP NAIL!
( Ugachi grunts )
( groans )
♪
( Kirito groaning )
( Eugeo gasps ) KIRITO!
( Kirito panting ) GOD.
V.R. NEVER HURT...
LIKE THIS!
Ugachi: YOU ROTTEN
LITTLE IUM BRAT!
TAKE MY ARM?! SHAME ME?!
( groans )
( roars )
( panting )
YOU PAY IN BLOOD!
I RIP YOU IN HALF,
EAT YOUR GUTS,
TEACH YOU LESSON IN SHAME!
( yells )
( Kirito yells )
( Eugeo gasps )
( Ugachi growls )
Eugeo: I’M SCARED...
BUT I CAN’T JUST STAND HERE!
I CAN’T MAKE THE SAME MISTAKE
I MADE WITH ALICE.
( Kirito groans )
( gasps )
( Ugachi growls )
( Kirito gasping )
( Ugachi panting )
Ugachi: DIE!
Eugeo: KIRITO!
THIS TIME...
I’LL FIGHT...
AND PROTECT MY FRIEND!
Kirito: RUN, EUGEO!
( Ugachi chuckles )
( Eugeo gags )
( Kirito gasps )
( Ugachi chuckles )
Kirito: EUGEO!
( panting )
EUGEO!
( Eugeo gasping )
♪
( Kirito gasps )
( Eugeo gags )
Kirito: EUGEO.
HANG ON, EUGEO, PLEASE!
Eugeo: W-WE MADE A PROMISE...
YOU, ME, AND ALICE.
WE PROMISED WE’D...
PROTECT EACH OTHER.
I COULDN’T SIX YEARS AGO,
BUT NOW, FINALLY...
I GOT TO.
( Kirito gasps )
♪
Kirito: THAT’S RIGHT.
I COULDN’T EITHER.
Ugachi: YOUR TURN NOW.
( Kirito yells )
Ugachi: NOW YOU DIE,
LIKE PATHETIC IUM YOU ARE!
♪
Kirito: MY NAME’S KIRITO,
KIRITO THE SWORDSMAN!
Ugachi: EITHER WAY, YOU DIE!
Kirito: MAYBE HE’S A FLUCTLIGHT,
LIKE EVERYONE ELSE.
( Ugachi roars )
STILL...
IF I DON’T KILL HIM,
HE’LL KILL US!
SWORD SKILL...
SONIC LEAP!
( Ugachi yells )
Kirito: FIGHT’S OVER.
YOUR BOSS IS DEAD.
YOU WANNA DIE THE SAME WAY,
THEN STEP UP!
BUT IF YOU WANNA LIVE, THEN GO
BACK TO THE DARK TERRITORY!
( goblins stammering )
( Kirito gasping )
HANG IN THERE.
( gasps )
SELKA! COME ON! WAKE UP!
( Selka groans )
KIRITO, WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
Kirito: WE CAME
TO TAKE YOU BACK HOME.
CAN YOU WALK OKAY?
Selka: IN A BIT.
MY LEGS ARE NUMB AND--
( yelps )
HEY, PUT ME DOWN!
Kirito: EUGEO NEEDS YOU.
HE’S HURT BAD.
HE’S DYING!
( Selka gasps )
M-MY SACRED ART SKILLS
AREN’T ENOUGH.
THE WOUND IS MUCH TOO DEEP.
Kirito: BUT YOU CAN
AT LEAST TRY.
YOU’RE ALICE’S SISTER.
YOU CAN DO THIS.
Selka: ALL I CAN HEAL
ARE SIMPLE SCRATCHES.
IF ALICE WERE HERE, SHE COULD
HELP HIM MORE THAN I COULD.
Kirito: LOOK,
EUGEO’S HURT ’CAUSE HE CAME
TO SAVE YOU, SELKA, NOT ALICE!
HE’S HERE ’CAUSE OF YOU!
( Selka gasps )
HMM.
THE USUAL HEALING ARTS
WOULD TAKE TOO LONG.
I’LL HAVE TO TRY A DANGEROUS
HIGH-LEVEL ONE INSTEAD.
KIRITO, I’M GOING TO NEED
YOUR HELP TO MAKE THIS WORK.
Kirito: OKAY, YOU GOT IT.
WHAT DO I DO?
Selka: GIVE ME YOUR LEFT HAND.
I’VE NEVER DONE THIS BEFORE,
AND IF I FAIL,
THERE’S A CHANCE
BOTH OF US WILL DIE.
I JUST WANT YOU TO KNOW THAT.
Kirito: IF THAT HAPPENS,
MAKE SURE IT ONLY KILLS ME.
LET’S DO THIS.
Selka: MM-HMM.
SYSTEM CALL.
TRANSFER HUMAN UNIT DURABILITY.
RIGHT HAND TO LEFT.
( Kirito wincing )
SHE’S TRANSFERRING HER LIFE
AND MINE TO HIM.
Selka: KIRITO...
CAN YOU KEEP GOING?
Kirito: I’M OKAY.
DON’T STOP. GIVE HIM MORE.
( wincing )
( gasps )
Girl: KIRITO, EUGEO,
COME AND FIND ME.
I AM WAITING...
AT THE TOP
OF THE CENTRAL CATHEDRAL.
( Kirito gasps )
Girl: I WILL WAIT THERE
FOR YOU BOTH.
Kirito: WHO WAS THAT?
( gasps )
( Selka gasps )
K-KIRITO!
( birds chirping )
( ax chops )
Eugeo: 50!
( panting )
Kirito: HOW’S YOUR WOUND DOING?
BETTER?
Eugeo: MUCH BETTER.
ALL I NEEDED WAS A DAY’S REST,
AND IT’S ALMOST HEALED.
( winces )
Kirito: I’VE BEEN
WANTING TO ASK YOU
ABOUT SOMETHING YOU SAID
BACK IN THE CAVE
RIGHT BEFORE YOU PASSED OUT.
I DON’T KNOW IF YOU REMEMBER,
BUT IT SOUNDED LIKE YOU THOUGHT
YOU, ALICE, AND ME
WERE FRIENDS BEFORE.
Eugeo: YES, I REMEMBER,
BUT WE ONLY JUST MET,
SO I DON’T KNOW
WHERE ALL THAT CAME FROM.
IT’S LIKE AT THAT MOMENT
I COULD SEE IT AS CLEAR AS DAY,
YOU, ALICE, AND ME.
WE WERE BORN ON THE SAME DAY
AND GREW UP TOGETHER HERE.
WE WERE EVEN TOGETHER
THE DAY ALICE WAS TAKEN AWAY.
Kirito: THAT’S WEIRD.
BY THE WAY,
WHEN SELKA WAS HEALING YOU,
YOU DIDN’T HAPPEN TO HEAR,
LIKE, A VOICE, DID YOU?
Eugeo: NO. I WAS
TOTALLY UNCONSCIOUS,
SO I DIDN’T HEAR A THING.
WHY? DID YOU HEAR A VOICE?
Kirito: NAH. GUESS I DREAMED IT.
FORGET I ASKED.
OH, WELL. TIME TO GET TO WORK.
Eugeo: RIGHT. HERE YOU GO.
( blade rings )
Kirito: I’M GONNA USE THIS.
( Eugeo gasps )
WAIT. BUT HOW--
YOU CAN--YOU CAN
WIELD THE SWORD?!
Kirito: YOU MIGHT
WANNA STAND BACK.
( deep breath )
’CAUSE OF THAT FIGHT
WITH THE GOBLINS,
NOW MY OBJECT CONTROL
AUTHORITY’S
HIGHER THAN THE SWORD’S.
HERE GOES.
( yells )
NICE.
( Eugeo gasps )
Kirito: I BET YOU CAN SWING IT
JUST AS EASY.
♪
( Eugeo gasps )
KIRITO, WILL YOU...
Kirito: HMM?
( hand scrapes )
Eugeo: WILL YOU
TEACH ME TO USE A SWORD?
( Kirito gasps )
Eugeo: IF SO,
I CAN GO GET ALICE BACK.
Kirito: EUGEO.
Eugeo: ALICE AND HER FAMILY
HAVE SUFFERED SO MUCH,
ALL BECAUSE OF ME.
♪
( blade thumps )
I COULDN’T SAVE HER.
I DON’T KNOW WHY,
BUT I COULDN’T,
AND, FOR THE PAST SIX YEARS,
I NEVER STOPPED REGRETTING IT.
I-I WANT TO BECOME STRONG
SO I-I CAN FIGHT,
SO I CAN KEEP
FROM MAKING THE SAME MISTAKE!
SO I CAN GET BACK
WHAT I LOST YEARS AGO.
THAT’S WHY--
THAT’S WHY I WANT
TO BECOME A SWORDSMAN!
Kirito: ALL RIGHT, THEN.
YOU’RE ON.
I’LL TEACH YOU
EVERYTHING I KNOW.
( Eugeo gasps )
Kirito: THE TRAINING’S
GONNA BE TOUGH, THOUGH.
Eugeo: THAT’S WHAT I’M HOPING.
BEFORE WE START,
DO YOU REMEMBER
WHAT YOUR SWORD STYLE IS CALLED?
Kirito: MM...
( grunts )
YEAH, I REMEMBER.
IT’S THE AINCRAD STYLE.
♪
( chuckles )
ALL RIGHT, EUGEO, FINISH IT.
( Eugeo grunts )
( yells )
( blade rings )
( man gasps ) HEY! LOOKIT!
Man #2: AT WHAT?
( townsfolk murmuring )
♪
Eugeo: THIS IS LIKE A DREAM.
I NEVER THOUGHT
THIS DAY WOULD COME.
I DIDN’T BELIEVE
IN DESTINY BEFORE,
BUT NOW...
KIRITO, MY CALLING
WASN’T MY DESTINY.
FOR THE PAST SIX YEARS,
I’VE BEEN WAITING
FOR YOU TO COME.
Kirito: YEAH, MAYBE YOU WERE.
BUT THEN AGAIN,
MAYBE I WOKE UP HERE
JUST SO I COULD MEET YOU.
( overlapping chatter,
laughter )
( musicians playing )
( Kirito sighing )
- Selka: WHY ARE YOU HERE ALONE?
- Kirito: HMM?
Kirito: OH. EUGEO’S
WITH YOUR DAD SOMEWHERE,
TALKIN’ ABOUT STUFF.
Selka: OH. I SEE.
I’M SURE HE’S GETTING
A LOT OF WELL-DESERVED PRAISE
FOR CHOPPING DOWN
THE DEMON TREE.
Kirito: AFTER ALL THE EFFORT
HE PUT IN, HE DESERVES IT.
Selka: I’VE DECIDED
TO STUDY HARDER,
SO I CAN BE AS GOOD
AT THE SACRED ARTS
AS MY SISTER WAS.
MM, NOT SO I CAN BE
LIKE HER, MIND YOU.
I WASN’T TRYING TO COPY HER
BY GOING TO THE CAVE.
I WOULD NEVER CROSS
INTO THE DARK TERRITORY.
BUT I THOUGHT BY TAKING
THE SAME PATH SHE DID,
I’D GET CLOSER TO HER SOMEHOW.
I WANTED TO GO IN
AS FAR AS I COULD.
IN A WAY, I GUESS
THE WHOLE POINT OF GOING THERE
WAS TO PROVE TO MYSELF
I COULD NEVER TAKE HER PLACE.
Kirito: NO,
BUT YOU’RE STILL AMAZING.
Selka: ME?
Kirito: WHAT OTHER GIRL HERE
COULD WALK INTO THAT DARK CAVE
ALL BY HERSELF?
I MEAN THAT’S SOMETHING
ONLY YOU COULD DO.
Selka: ONLY I COULD DO?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN BY THAT?
Kirito: YOU’RE YOU,
NOT ALICE’S REPLACEMENT,
AND YOU GOT SKILLS
NO ONE ELSE HERE HAS.
WITH A LITTLE PRACTICE,
YOU’LL MASTER ’EM.
( Selka giggles )
( townsfolk gasp )
Gasfut: MAY I HAVE
YOUR ATTENTION, PLEASE!
THE GREATEST WISH OF RULID’S
FOUNDERS HAS BEEN FULFILLED.
THE DEMON TREE
HAS BEEN FELLED AT LAST!
( all cheering )
Gasfut: SO LET US ALL GIVE
THANKS TO EUGEO, SON OF ORICK!
( all cheering )
Gasfut: ACCORDING TO THE LAWS,
WHEN ONE FINISHES THEIR CALLING,
THEY HAVE EARNED
THE RIGHT TO CHOOSE
WHAT THEIR NEXT CALLING
WILL BE.
GO AHEAD, EUGEO.
MAKE YOUR CHOICE.
( wind blowing )
( townsfolk murmuring )
Eugeo: I...
Gasfut: HMM?
Eugeo: I WILL BECOME
A SWORDSMAN!
- ( Gasfut gasps )
- ( townsfolk murmuring )
Eugeo: I SHALL TRAIN HARD
AND JOURNEY TO CENTORIA.
( Gasfut gasps )
EUGEO, WHAT COULD YOU POSSIBLY--
NO. I WON’T QUESTION YOU.
IT IS YOUR CHURCH-GIVEN RIGHT
TO CHOOSE YOUR NEXT CALLING.
AS RULID’S ELDER,
I APPROVE EUGEO’S
NEW CALLING AS SWORDSMAN!
( all cheering )
( bell tolls )
♪
Eugeo: SELKA.
Selka: MM?
EUGEO.
Eugeo: BEFORE I GO, I-I WANTED
TO TELL YOU SOMETHING.
Selka: OH? WHAT IS IT?
Eugeo: MY GOAL...
IS TO GO TO CENTORIA
AND BRING ALICE BACK HERE.
Selka: I THOUGHT SO.
Eugeo: FOR THE PAST SIX YEARS,
IT’S ALL
I’VE BEEN THINKING ABOUT.
BUT WITH MY CALLING, I HAD
NO IDEA HOW I’D GO ABOUT IT.
( Selka sighs )
Eugeo: THEN KIRITO
SUDDENLY SHOWED UP,
AND BRINGING ALICE BACK
DIDN’T SEEM HOPELESS ANYMORE.
FOR SOME REASON,
I FEEL LIKE I CAN DO ANYTHING
WITH HIM AROUND.
YOU AND YOUR FAMILY
HAVE SUFFERED SO MUCH,
ALL ON ACCOUNT OF ME,
SO I’LL BRING ALICE BACK
AND MAKE THINGS RIGHT.
HAVE FAITH IN ME,
AND WAIT FOR OUR RETURN.
Selka: WELL, I CAN’T STOP YOU,
BUT IF YOU INSIST...
Eugeo: I DO.
Selka: OKAY. I SHALL WAIT.
JUST MAKE SURE
THE THREE OF YOU COME BACK.
( Eugeo gasps )
( sighs ) MM-HMM.
I’LL MAKE SURE WE ALL
COME BACK SAFE! PROMISE!
- ( Kirito chuckles )
- Selka: GOOD LUCK.
♪
Eugeo: SORRY
TO KEEP YOU WAITING.
Kirito: NO WORRIES.
Eugeo: WELL, THEN,
ARE YOU READY?
Kirito: UH-HUH.
Eugeo: I WONDER
WHAT CENTORIA WILL BE LIKE.
Kirito: WHO KNOWS?
( chuckles ) IT’S GOTTA BE
WAY BIGGER THAN RULID, RIGHT?
( Eugeo laughs )
I CERTAINLY HOPE SO.
( thunder rumbling )
IT LOOKS LIKE RAIN’S COMING.
WE SHOULD HURRY
BEFORE WE GET CAUGHT IN IT.
WHAT’S WRONG?
Kirito: HUH? WHAT?
Eugeo: NEVER MIND. SHALL WE GO?
( Kirito chuckles )
YEAH.
( thunder rumbling )
♪
( singing in Japanese )
♪ THE IRIS TO YOU ♪